A Guide to the Edward H. Peeples, Jr. Papers, n.d., 1915, 1920s-2005
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
Edward H. Peeples, Jr. n.d., 1915, 1920s-2005
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library
M 342
33 linear feet.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Edward H. Peeples, Jr. in 2003 and 2005
Biographical Information
Dr. Edward H. Peeples, Jr. is Emeritus Associate Professor of Preventive Medicine and Community Health at Virginia Commonwealth University where he taught for more than thirty years. Peeples made most of his academic contributions in the fields of medical behavioral science, public health, epidemiology and sociology. But much of his research and writing dealt with contemporary issues of social justice and he spent most of his adult life as a civil rights advocate involved in a variety of human rights reforms in Virginia and other places across the south.
Born in Richmond on 20 April 1935, Peeples received a B.S. in Health and Physical Education from Richmond Professional Institute (now VCU) in 1957. He began his civil rights activity in 1955 while a student at RPI. In late 1959, soon after being discharged from the US Navy, he became a volunteer with the American Friends Service Committee in Prince Edward County, Virginia which had closed its public schools rather than racially integrate them. In February 1960, he participated in the first of Richmond's lunch counter sit-ins. He later did extensive field work and interviewing in Prince Edward which led to his Masters thesis, A Perspective on the Prince Edward County Virginia School Issue, at the University of Pennsylvania in 1963. From this he produced several documents, some of which were later incorporated into reports and briefings for the United States Commission on Civil Rights; the U.S. Department of Justice; and the U.S. Office of Education in their efforts to find a resolution to the Prince Edward County school closing issue.
Peeples received a M.A. in Human Relations (Intergroup Relations) from the University of Pennsylvania in 1963; and a Ph.D. from the University of Kentucky in Sociology with a Concentration in Medical Behavioral Science in 1972. He began his teaching career at the Medical College of Virginia and the Richmond Professional Institute in 1963, prior to their merger in 1968 forming Virginia Commonwealth University. During his long academic career, Dr. Peeples taught, conducted research, consulted and published in the fields of medical behavioral science (behavioral factors governing clinical practice in the helping professions), behavioral epidemiology (behavioral causes, complications and consequences of disease, injury and disability), public health and community medicine, violence prevention, research methodology, intergroup relations (including race and ethnic relations and minority health), and sociology.
He was appointed by the Richmond City Council in the early 1980s to the Commission on Human Relations where he was elected both Vice-Chair and Chairman and also was appointed to the Richmond Environmental Commission in the early 1990s. Since his retirement in October 1995, Peeples has continued his efforts to help document the struggle for Civil Rights in Virginia and has worked with historians, researchers, numerous repositories, and with the Martin Luther King, Jr. Commission of the Virginia General Assembly. He is married and has four daughters and two grandchildren.
Higher Education:
Ph.D., University of Kentucky, 1972, Concentration in Medical Behavioral Science, major: Sociology, minor: Anthropology. Dissertation: Rank Differentiation and Somatic Disease: A Systematically Derived Inventory of Propositions
M.A., University of Pennsylvania, 1963, Human Relations (Intergroup Relations). Thesis: The Prince Edward County Virginia School Issue
B.S., Virginia Commonwealth University (formally Richmond Professional Institute), 1957, Health and Physical Education, Honor Graduate Award for Leadership, Outstanding Senior Athlete Award, 1956-57.
Academic Appointments at Virginia Commonwealth University:
1995-present Associate Professor Emeritus of Preventive Medicine and Community Health
1976-1995 Associate Professor of Preventive Medicine, Dept. of Preventive Medicine and Community Health (DPMCH) and Department of Biostatistics
1991-1992 Scholar-in-Residence, University Honors Program
1991-1995 Faculty Research Associate, Center for Public Service
1972-1976 Assistant Professor of Preventive Medicine, DPMCH
1968-1972 Assistant Professor of Sociology and Preventive Medicine, Departments of Sociology/Anthropology and DPMCH
1963-1965 Instructor in Sociology, School of Nursing, Medical College of Virginia
1963-1964 Instructor in Sociology, Richmond Professional Institute, part-time
Academic Appointments at Other Institutions:
1985-1986 Lecturer in Medical Sociology, University of Richmond, part-time
1967-1968 Instructor in Medical Sociology, Dept. of Behavioral Science, Colleges of Medicine and Dentistry, University of Kentucky, Lexington
Scope and Content
The Papers of Dr. Edward H. Peeples, Jr. document his long career in education and public health and in his activities as a promoter of social justice in a variety of human rights reforms in Virginia and other places across the south. The collection is especially strong in the areas of race and discrimination, poverty, public health and school inequality from the 1950s through the 1980s including materials relating to the closing of public schools in Virginia's Prince Edward County. Other subject areas include the early history of Virginia Commonwealth University (1967-early 1970s) and various programs associated with the University, human relations in Richmond and Virginia, and the aftermath of Hurricane Camille (1969). The materials in the collection include a large of amount of correspondence, reports, and publications. Also included in the collection are newspaper and journal clippings, photographs (many of Prince Edward County and other areas in Virginia taken by Peeples), slides, phonographs, and other materials. The bulk of the collection dates from 1950s through 2005.
Researchers should also consult the finding aid for an earlier but much smaller collection donated by Peeples to Special Collections and Archives, M 68. This collection also consists of Dr. Peeples' studies in the field of hunger, poverty, and racial issues in the United States and abroad (South Africa). There is considerable information on the fight for integration in Virginia in the 1960s, including materials associated with the Prince Edward County school issue in the late 1950s and early 1960s.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into four series consisting of Professional and Biographical (materials related to Dr. Peeples' work as a research professor), Broad Subject Areas (thirteen major topics randing from race to preventative medicine), Miscellaneous Topics, and Miscellaneous audio and visual materials (slides, audio and video recordings, phonographs, photographs), publications, ephemera, and oversize materials.
Contents List
- Professional and Biographical 1950s-2000 (Box 1-7)
  Alphabetical
  - Articles from medical journals, 1953, 1957, 1960, 1963, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "Awareness of Sickle Cell Anemia among Negro of Richmond, VA" by John C. Lane and Robert B. Scot, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bereavement Program Task Force, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Biographical Information (Peeples) from ASBAME newsletter, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Book reviews, reports by Peeples, 1978 and 1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Building of Community in Richmond, n.d., 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bus Lecture Technique for Teaching about Life in the City, includes course materials, 1971-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Care and Feeding of Community Coalitions, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Cartoons (Editorial and other newspaper cartoons) miscellaneous, (1 of 2), n.d., 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Cartoons (Editorial and other newspaper cartoons) miscellaneous, (2 of 2), n.d., 1980s-1990s (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Celebration of Teaching (Second Annual), Virginia Commonwealth University, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Children in Poverty, n.d., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Commission on Human Relations, Departing Remarks by Peeples - Richmond, VA, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Community events - Richmond, Virginia, 1971, 1978, 1981-1984, 1990, 1995 -1996 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Community Involvement - Good News!, celebrity correspondence, 1982 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Community Involvement - Good News!, Project (folder 1 of 2), 1982 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Community Involvement - Good News!, Project (folder 2 of 2), 1982 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Community Involvement - Good News!, promotional materials, 1982 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Community Involvement - Good News!, thank you letters, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Conferences and retreats attended by Peeples, 1984, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Continuing Medical Education Conference, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence (Includes letter from Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence (Recruitment to MCV)-, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence (Recruitment to MCV) -, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence, January - May 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, June - December, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Behavioral Science, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Behavioral Science, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Directory of Faculty and Courses in Injury and Violence Prevention, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Lecture on Prevention, c. 1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Behavioral Science - M I, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Behavioral Science - M I, 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Behavioral Science - M I, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Electives, 1970-1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Minority Issues in Public Health, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Preventative Medicine - M II, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), School of Nursing, 1963-1965 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Social Epidemiology, 1979-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Survey of Intentional Injuries, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Medical College of Virginia (MCV), Survey of Public Health Behavior, 1990-1995 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - University of Kentucky, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - University of Richmond, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Honors Module - A Critical Look at Contemporary Medicine, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Honors Seminar as Scholar in residence - "Things Ethereal and Methodical", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Medical Sociology, 1969-1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Sociology Courses, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University and Medical College of Virginia miscellaneous courses, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University and Medical College of Virginia miscellaneous courses, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Courses and seminars by Peeples - Virginia Commonwealth University and Medical College of Virginia Miscellaneous Courses miscellaneous courses, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Dictionary of Prevention" by Edward Peeples and Jacqueline Admire, 1988-1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation - Rank Differentiation and Somatic Disease: A Systematically Derived Inventory of Propositions (Peeples' dissertation) pages 1-150 - original typescript, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Dissertation - Rank Differentiation and Somatic Disease: A Systematically Derived Inventory of Propositions (Peeples' dissertation) pages 151-275 - original typescript, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Dissertation - Rank Differentiation and Somatic Disease: A Systematically Derived Inventory of Propositions (Peeples' dissertation) bibliography, appendices, notes, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Editorials by Peeples, 1958 - 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Editorials by Peeples, 1965 - 1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Editorials by Peeples, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Editorials by Peeples, 1990 - 1999 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Erik Esposito wrongful death case - Peeples as expert witness (Court documents), 1993 - 1994 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - "The Expanse of Sociological Medicine," Journal of Sociological Medicine, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Expert Witness (Peeples) - Robert Burton racial discrimination case, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Expert Witness (Peeples) - Erik Esposito wrongful death case (see box 5), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Expert Witness (Peeples) - Infant C v. Jerome Steven Gordon, et al., 1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Expert Witness (Peeples) - Paula Jones child abuse case, 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Expert Witness (Peeples) - Richmond Tenants Organization, Inc. v. Richmond Redevelopment and Housing Authority, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Expert Witness (Peeples) - Susan Weiss v. City of Richmond Public Schools n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Faculty Evaluations, n.d. 1992 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Family - Postcards representing travel of wealthy friends of the family who the mother of Peeples worked for, n.d., 1906-1919 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Family - Postcards representing travel of wealthy friends of the family who the mother of Peeples worked for, n.d., 1910 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Governors School Mentors for Medical College of Virginia (MCV), n.d., 1989 n.d., 1989 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - "Human Behavior and Disease: A Systems Theory of the relationship between the cell, the Psyche, and Society" by Peeples and Werner Dutz, c. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Human Behavior and Disease: A Systems Theory of the relationship between the cell, the Psyche, and Society" - manuscript for book, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - "The Journey from Byrdland" by Peeples, c. 1980s (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Late 19th century notebook filled with poems clipped from periodicals, 19th century (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Lectures, presentations, and workshops by Peeples, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Lectures, presentations, and workshops by Peeples, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Lectures, presentations, and workshops by Peeples, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Lectures, presentations, and workshops by Peeples, 1980s (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Lectures, presentations, and workshops by Peeples, 1990s (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Letter to Hanover Co. Public Schools from Peeples, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Letters of Recommendation supporting Peeples' promotion at VCU/MCV, 1975, 1976, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - "Living Systems: Basic Concepts" by James G. Miller, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - "Man and His Environment" MCV syllabus, 1960s (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Media and Press Contacts, c. 1970s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Behavioral Science Group, 1972, c. 1977 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Committee on Intergroup Education (CIE), n.d., 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Desegregation and Nursing Schools (Peeples and C.W. Pollard), c. 1967-1980s (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Elderhostel Program, 1983-1987, 1989 1983-1987, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Lead Poisoning in Richmond, VA - 2 reports, n.d., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Memorandum, news clippings, 1986, 1990, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Richmond Healthways Study, n.d., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Richmond Healthways Study - Coding Key, n.d., 1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Richmond Healthways Study Guide, 1973 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Richmond Healthways Study Guide Questionnaire Analysis Copy, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Student Projects - "Behavioral Factors in Medicine," 1977-1990 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Medical College of Virginia (MCV) - Student Projects - "Behavioral Factors in Medicine," 1977-1986 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Methodology V. I. (1 of 2) - Ten Perimeters of the Sphere of Scientific Pursuit; A Preliminary, Topographical Outline of the Various Dimensions of Scientific Inquiry, ca. 1971 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Methodology V. I. (2 of 2) - Ten Perimeters of the Sphere of Scientific Pursuit; A Preliminary, Topographical Outline of the Various Dimensions of Scientific Inquiry, ca. 1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Methodology V. II. (1 of 2) 1990 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Methodology V. II. (2 of 2) 1990 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Memberships and donations, Peeples, 1964-1970 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous articles by Peeples, 1968-1996 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous biographical items (Peeples), drawing, card, cartoon, publication from University of Kentucky, list of Governor George Allen's [1990s] office staff, n.d., 1965-1968, 1990s, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence from students and colleagues, 1975-1992 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous essays and papers by Peeples, n.d., 1971, 1971, 1973, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous lecture notes, essays, and other writings by Peeples, 1960s-1980s (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous teaching materials, (folder 1 of 2) c. 1960s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Miscellaneous teaching materials, (folder 2 of 2) c. 1960s-1990s (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - National Public Radio shows - correspondence, 1985, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles regarding Peeples, 1942, 1950s, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles regarding Peeples, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles regarding Peeples, 1970s (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles regarding Peeples, 1980s (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper and magazine articles regarding Peeples, 1990s (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper article regarding Peeples, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Non-Violence and community service correspondence, n.d., 1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "A Perspective of the Prince Edward Country School Issue" - by Peeples, Master's Theses, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Pre-Enlistment Variables Related to the Performance and Adjustments of Navy Recruits" by John A. Plug, includes letter, 2 1962 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Prince Edward County, Virginia: A Study in Infamy" by J. Rupert Picott and Edward Peeples, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Proposals by Peeples -"Exploratory Study of Medical Compliance among Hypertensive Patients," 1975-1976 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Proposals by Peeples -"A List of Optimum Data Elements" (LODE) for Sexual Assault and family Violence Services Providers, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Proposals by Peeples - miscellaneous, d.d., 1970s - 1990s (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Proposals by Peeples -"A Planning Proposal to Develop the VCU Prevention Institute", 1988 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Proposals by Peeples -"A Proposal for the Creation of a Youth Development Experience known as Richmonde," 1994-1998 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Proposals by Peeples -"A Proposal for an Injury Prevention, Treatment, and Research Center", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Raleigh Review [VCU Social Work faculty publication] - Interview of Edward Peeples, Spring 1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Richmond Professional Institute (RPI) - Handbook for Student Government Association Representatives" organized and drafted by Peeples, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Richmond Professional Institute (RPI) and Virginia Commonwealth History - newspaper articles, publications, yearbook pictures, 1950s, 1985, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Statewide conference on Cooperative Approaches to Civil Rights (VA), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Statistics and Methodology Cards n.d. (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Student Papers by Peeples, University of Pennsylvania, 1961-1963 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Student Papers by Peeples, folder 1 of 2, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Student Papers by Peeples, folder 2 of 2, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - "Study of Public School Property Inequalities between Blacks and Whites in Virginia, 1963 and before (1962-1963)", first draft by Peeples, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Thank you letters by Peeples, 1965, 1971-1980, 1982-1992, 1985-1994 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - "Toward a Unified Theory of Behavior: The General Systems Approach" by Peeples, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - VCU Task Force on Crimes Affecting VCU - report, correspondence, article in the VCU Voice n.d. (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - "Violence and Other Threatening Themes in Five Virginia Game Arcades," by Peeples, graphs and charts, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Virginia Breast and Cervical Cancer Program, n.d., 1997 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) List of initial faculty, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Department of Sociology - Sociological Research Symposium, 1975, 1979, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University (VCU) Department of Sociology - "Time Out Week" visiting scholars including Ivan Svitak, 1969. Includes newspaper articles on Alexander Dubcek, 1993 and 1994 (Box 7, Folder 34)